ROBBIE WALLER, MENG (HONS) PGDIP

☑ rob@robbiewaller.co.uk

 $\Box +447523207689$

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an enthusiastic Nuclear Engineer, specialising in assurance and management of nuclear operations. I have unique experience of operating and managing nuclear reactors in the USA and the UK. I now intend to apply my knowledge to assurance activities in the UK nuclear power sector. Operating as an individual and leading teams, I have a proven track record in being highly adaptable across multiple areas of the nuclear enterprise. This broad baseline makes me highly suitable to an assurance role. I maintain a questioning attitude to the status-quo, underpinned by a strong sense of moral courage and backed up by absolute professionalism.

EDUCATION

Engineering Charge Qualification, Naval Reactors, Washington DC	2018
POSTGRADUATE DIPLOMA, CRANFIELD UNIVERSITY, NUCLEAR REACTOR TECHNOLOGY	2013
MENG (HONS), MECHANICAL ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHAMPTON	2011

EXPERIENCE

SUBMARINE ASSURANCE OFFICER, NAVY COMMAND

2018-PRESENT

- Responsible for providing assurance that the Submarine Service operates within its Nuclear Authorisation Conditions as well as the health, safety and environmental constraints of the Defence Maritime Regulator (DMR).
- Act as the focal point for regulator interaction. Conduct independent 3rd party nuclear assurance audits across the organisation. Identify, manage and correct nuclear non-compliance findings as well as DMR findings.
- Analyse data from Organisational Learning reports to identify adverse trends in safety culture. Communicate and implement lessons learnt to prevent reoccurrence.

SAFETY DELIVERY MANAGER, NUCLEAR PROPULSION PROJECT TEAM, MOD 2018 - 2019

- Acted as project lead for a nuclear engineering safety case development programme. Responsible for interpreting experimental and calculated data to provide recommendations on safety case limitations for future operation.
- Responsible for data analysis of studies conducted by the Technical Authority (Rolls Royce) and the Independent Nuclear Authority (Wood Group). Made recommendations to the Defence Nuclear Safety Regulator that plants were safe to operate, subsequently extending the operational life of 2 nuclear plants.
- Acted as an Assistant Duly Authorised Person (ADAP).

ELECTRICAL OFFICER & ASSISTANT ENGINEER

2016-2018

- 2000 hours experience as Qualified Critical plant supervisor and 50 days of experience as Shutdown plant supervisor. Successfully led and co-ordinated 6 reactor startups and shutdowns.
- Responsible for \$1.5 billion submarine alongside, managing a team of 25 technical specialists for 24-hour periods.

- Responsible for Audit and Surveillance programme. As an inspector, monitoring conduct of routine
 plant maintenance and operations to ensure compliance with procedures, work practices and SSHE
 arrangments.
- Passed professional examinations and interviews at Naval Reactors in Washington DC (PNEO), giving certification to operate as the Chief Engineer on a USN nuclear plant.
- Qualified as a Duly Authorised Person (DAP), providing oversight to complex nuclear operations including cool downs, control rod testing, switchboard maintenance and live plant drill periods.

SUBMARINE SUSTAINABLE MANNING PROGRAMME

2015 - 2016

- Co-ordinated a study with independent consultants, analysing novel methods of staffing Nuclear control rooms with contractors during maintenance periods.
- Conducted training needs analysis of a shut-down nuclear operator in order to enable contractorisation. Resulted in 2 contractors undertaking trial periods of nuclear operation on a submarine.

NAVAL NUCLEAR POWER TRAINING COMMAND

2014-2015

- Selected by senior management as top student of 18 candidates on an engineering graduate scheme to undertake a prestigious 3-year exchange with the US Navy.
- Undertook 6-months of academically rigorous training and a further 6-month period of rotational shift work on a prototype S5W reactor design at Naval Nuclear Power Training Unit Charleston.
- Certified by the US Navy and the US Department of Energy to act as Nuclear Engineering Officer of the Watch, qualifying early, with above average marks in all assessments.

ASSISTANT MARINE ENGINEERING OFFICER (TRAINING)

2012 - 2014

- Selected for a 2-year Royal Navy graduate scheme, comprising theoretical and practical training in mechanical systems, electronics, refrigeration, nuclear theory, reactor design, nuclear health physics and nuclear systems.
- Qualified as a Nuclear engineering spaces watch-keeper and a Nuclear electrical panel operator.
- Conducted 3-month period of independent research into a Tritium monitoring facility in a radiochemistry lab. Designed, ran and evaluated experiments using a Liquid Scintillation Counter (LSC) resulting in the development of standard operating procedures and commissioning for future testing.
- Conducted a technical review of state-of-the-art LSC techniques for solid sampling, the output of which was a presentation to an industry partner on methods for optimising their 'tritium analysis in solids' techniques.

FURTHER INFORMATION

- Fluency in technical and conversational French including 6-months of engineering study at the French Naval Academy.
- Professional Memberships: Chartered Engineer, Institute of Mechanical Engineering (Submitted, awaiting interview).
- Security Cleared to a high government standard.
- Interests: RYA Yachtmaster Instructor, Motorcycles, conversational German.